<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Structure &#43; Semantics on Editing EPUBs for NNELS</title>
    <link>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Structure &#43; Semantics on Editing EPUBs for NNELS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/intro/</guid>
      <description>The contents in this section are in no significant order - where you choose to begin is up to you. What&amp;rsquo;s important is that you check that each of these components are properly marked up in the book.
TALK ABOUT WHY THIS IS IMPORTANT
Our goal is to create a book that uses meaningful HTML markup to indicate page structure and text language. Meaningful HTML markup makes it easier for users of assistive technology to understand the book&amp;rsquo;s structure and the arrangement of content, which improves navigation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockquotes</title>
      <link>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/blockquotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/blockquotes/</guid>
      <description>A blockquote represents a section that is quoted from another source. It&amp;rsquo;s represented by the &amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt; element.
Often times, you will see books that use the &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; or paragraph element, instead of the semantically correct &amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;. This &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; element is often followed by a class=&amp;quot;quote&amp;quot; attribute, or a similiar class value (we&amp;rsquo;ll talk more about getting rid of classes later).
Using the &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; element when a more specific element is appropriate is a violation of the HTML specification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bold and italics</title>
      <link>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/bold-italics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/bold-italics/</guid>
      <description>Strong vs. Bold. Emphasis vs. Italics. What&amp;rsquo;s the difference? And what should we do about it?
In HTML5, there are two types of &amp;ldquo;bold&amp;rdquo; - represented by the &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt; and the &amp;lt;b&amp;gt; elements. There also two types of &amp;ldquo;italics&amp;rdquo; - represented by the &amp;lt;em&amp;gt; and the &amp;lt;i&amp;gt; elements. Each of these elements conveys different information to the reading system. If you&amp;rsquo;re curious about their uses, you can explore the links in the References.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context breaks</title>
      <link>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/context-breaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/context-breaks/</guid>
      <description>A context break is a thematic break, such as, a scene change in a story, or a transition to another topic within a section of a book.
The &amp;lt;hr /&amp;gt;, or horizontal rule, element is used to represent a context break. The use of the hr element to indicate context breaks allows assistive technologies to inform users of this shift in thought, time, location, or similiar.
You may come across all sorts of different, and creative, ways that are used to denote a change in context in a book (see Examples).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Images</title>
      <link>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/images/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landmarks</title>
      <link>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/landmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/landmarks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lists</title>
      <link>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/lists/</guid>
      <description>If you come across a list of items in a book, you need to check that it&amp;rsquo;s tagged appropriately so that users can easily navigate through it. The ability to move quickly and effectively through long lists is a key reading need and often overlooked as an accessibility feature.
Sighted readers rarely notice the advantage of being able to quickly skim a list, determine if it&amp;rsquo;s of any interest and/or selectively read items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes</title>
      <link>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/notes/</guid>
      <description>Notes need to be properly identified in the text as either footnotes or endnotes.
To do this, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to apply the appropriate epub:type and aria roles to both the references and their notes.
Since notes are formatted consistently throughout the entire book, this means you can use regex to update all of them at once into the correct format.
EPUB 2 vs EPUB 3 notes The difference between EPUB 2 and EPUB 3 notes is one of semantics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page titles</title>
      <link>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/page-titles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/page-titles/</guid>
      <description>Each xhtml file in a book has a title. This title can be found at the top of the page in the &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; element.
Meaningful titles allow readers to find and navigate to pages without having to first read them. Assistive technologies typically announce the title of each page when it&amp;rsquo;s first loaded in a user agent.
It&amp;rsquo;s commonplace to see just the title of the book in the &amp;lt;title&amp;gt; element on every xhtml page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sections and headings</title>
      <link>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/sections-and-headings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/sections-and-headings/</guid>
      <description>For readers to be able to follow and understand the content, you need to clearly identify the sections of the book. Clearly grouping and identifying content enables better navigation by anyone reading using an assistive technology. To give the book a meaningful structure, follow the steps below.
Add a section or an aside element All the primary and secondary sections of a book need to be encapsulated in either a &amp;lt;section&amp;gt; or an &amp;lt;aside&amp;gt; element, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tables</title>
      <link>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flittle8.github.io/cupper/patterns/structure-and-semantics/tables/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>